<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Tokhy's hub</title>
<link href="https://tokiesan.github.io/atom-gsoc.xml" rel="self"/>
<updated>2023-07-17T12:25:47+03:00</updated>
<author>
<name>Ahmed Gamal Eltokhy</name>
</author>
<id>https://tokiesan.github.io</id>

<entry>
<title>GSoC'23 LibreOffice Proposal</title><summary>LibreOffice Google Summer of Code 23 Proposal</summary>
<link href="https://tokiesan.github.io/blogposts/gsoc/libreoffice-prop.html"/>
<updated>2023-06-02T20:02:39+03:00</updated>
<id>https://tokiesan.github.io/blogposts/gsoc/libreoffice-prop.html</id>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Pilot: Joining LibreOffice in GSoC'23</title><summary>Joining LibreOffice in GSoC'23: A Short Introduction</summary>
<link href="https://tokiesan.github.io/blogposts/gsoc/pilot.html"/>
<updated>2023-06-02T20:03:54+03:00</updated>
<id>https://tokiesan.github.io/blogposts/gsoc/pilot.html</id>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>GSoC Week 1 Report: Remembering Digital Signatures</title><summary>In the first week of GSoC, the focus was on implementing an option to remember digital signatures session-wise in LibreOffice. The initial setup involved creating a testing environment with numerous certificates, filing a bug on Bugzilla, and exploring the relevant codebase. The main workflow of the patch is now complete, with the next steps being to link the resigning function to the saving request and cache certificates and signatures per session.</summary>
<link href="https://tokiesan.github.io/blogposts/gsoc/week_1_report.html"/>
<updated>2023-06-10T19:44:36+03:00</updated>
<id>https://tokiesan.github.io/blogposts/gsoc/week_1_report.html</id>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Week 2 Report</title><summary>**Week 2 Report - Summary** Implemented the ability to remember digital signatures, eliminating the need for manual signing on each save. Also working on a caching mechanism to improve certificate loading performance. More details [here](https://gerrit.libreoffice.org/c/core/+/152687) and [here](https://gerrit.libreoffice.org/c/core/+/153113). Stay tuned for further updates on this ongoing work.</summary>
<link href="https://tokiesan.github.io/blogposts/gsoc/week_2_report.html"/>
<updated>2023-06-17T21:18:46+03:00</updated>
<id>https://tokiesan.github.io/blogposts/gsoc/week_2_report.html</id>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Week 3 Report: More Certificate Manager Improvements</title><summary>In the Week 3 report of my GSoC'23 journey at LibreOffice, I made significant improvements to the certificate manager integration and caching. I successfully implemented a patch to hide the certificate manager button when not available, laying the groundwork for future enhancements. Additionally, I worked on certificate caching to optimize access and reduce loading delays. The certificates view was revamped with a user-friendly tree view, simplifying navigation and management. Challenges ahead include further customization of certificate managers, improving the UI for viewing certificates, and completing the certificate caching feature.</summary>
<link href="https://tokiesan.github.io/blogposts/gsoc/week_3_report.html"/>
<updated>2023-06-24T10:28:32+03:00</updated>
<id>https://tokiesan.github.io/blogposts/gsoc/week_3_report.html</id>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Week 4 Report: Custom Certificate Manager and Certificate UI Enhancements</title><summary>This week in GSoC'23 at LibreOffice, progress was made on custom certificate manager integration and certificate UI improvements. The custom certificate manager option is nearing completion, pending review, while work continues on transforming the certificate display with a tree view for easier navigation. Upcoming tasks include finalizing these features and continue working on UI improvements.</summary>
<link href="https://tokiesan.github.io/blogposts/gsoc/week_4_report.html"/>
<updated>2023-07-03T12:07:28+03:00</updated>
<id>https://tokiesan.github.io/blogposts/gsoc/week_4_report.html</id>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Week 5 & 6 Report</title><summary>During Weeks 5 and 6 of GSoC at LibreOffice, I completed two patches: one for customized certificate managers, resolving related bugzilla issues, and another for improving the certificate chooser dialog. I also started working on search and filter functionalities for the dialog. Progress is being made to enhance the user experience and flexibility of certificate management in LibreOffice.</summary>
<link href="https://tokiesan.github.io/blogposts/gsoc/week_5_6_report.html"/>
<updated>2023-07-17T12:25:47+03:00</updated>
<id>https://tokiesan.github.io/blogposts/gsoc/week_5_6_report.html</id>
</entry>
</feed>
